Guide to the Yale University Master of Fine Arts Theses in Photography
Yale University Arts Library
Yale University Master of Fine Arts Theses in Photography
1972-2017
AOB 36
Yale University Arts Library
75
(338 boxes)
The collection consists of over 300 individual MFA theses in photography from 1971 to the present.
Yale University. School of Art. Photography Program
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the School of Art.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Most of the collection is housed at the Library Shelving Facility and must be requested at least 48 hours in advance.
Only use copies of magnetic or digital media may be viewed.
Biographical / Historical
Originally part of the Graphic Design graduate program, Photography became an independent MFA program in the early 1970s. This two-year course of study provides instruction in black-and-white and color photography as well as nonsilver processes and digital image production. The program is committed to a broad definition of photography as a lens-based medium open to a variety of expressive means.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of over 300 individual Master of Fine Arts theses from 1971 to the present. The theses are most often in the format of a portfolio of photographic prints, though some theses are also in book form. Individual records for the MFA theses are also available in the library catalog.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by year of completion/graduation and then alphabetically by student's last name within each year.
Photography; Theses; Yale University. School of Art
- MFA Theses
  - Art School Pictures, 1971, O'Brien, Michael; 24 prints, 1 submission form, 2 pages of notes, 1 miscellaneous document; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 4.5 x 7 inches, including mat (Box 1)
    General note
    Keywords: portraits
  - Photographs, 1972; Atchley, John; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 4.5 x 5.5 inches to 7.5 x 9 inches, including mat (Box 3)
    Keywords: abstract (fine arts style), nature photography
  - A Photographic Experience, 1972; Branch, Harrison; 14 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 14 x 16 inches (Box 4)
    Keywords: Connecticut, nature photography, landscapes (representations), close-up views
  - [Untitled], 1972; Kamuch, Josef H.; 23 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 9 x 12 inches, including mat (Box 5)
  - Ten Platinum Prints, 1973; Crawford, William E.; 10 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; platinum prints; Measurements:; range from 13.5 x 12 inches to 13.5 x 16 inches (Box 2)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), cityscapes (representations)
  - War in the East: 1941-1943: A collection of photographs, 1973; Levinthal, David; 14 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form, 1 list of works, 1 miscellaneous document; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 6.75 x 7 inches to 8.75 x 7 inches, including mat (Box 6)
    Keywords: still lifes, close-up views
  - Seventeen Photographs of Coney Island, 1973; Thompson, Jerry L.; 17 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 7)
    Keywords: portraits, landscapes (representations), Coney Island
  - The Degree Presentation: Seven Prints - Brantville, New Brunswick, 1973; Wells-Blauvelt, Melinda; 7 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 8)
    Keywords: New Brunswick-Canada, portraits, children (people by age group), documentary photography, rural areas
  - The Quarry, 1974; Johnson, Peter Winfield; 35 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 13.5 inches (Box 9)
    Keywords: industrial districts, close-up view, still lifes
  - [Untitled], 1974; Nesbit, Charles C.; 3 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10)
    Keywords: abstract (fine arts style), flash photography
  - [Untitled], 1974; Osinski, Christine; 24 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 4 x 5.5 inches (Box 11)
    Keywords: still lifes, close-up views, portraits
  - Photographs Taken at the Intersection of a Wall and the Ground, 1974; Schwartz, Elliot; 12 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 11 inches (Box 12)
    Keywords: close-up views, abstract (fine arts style)
  - [Untitled], 1975; Lee, Baldwin S.; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 13)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), cityscapes (representations), night photography
  - [Untitled], 1975; Kent, David; 12 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 3.5 x 5 inches, including mat (Box 14)
    Keywords: documentary photography, cityscapes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1975; Kovacs, Andrea; 4 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photocopies; Measurements:; 20 x 85 inches (Box 15)
    Keywords: portraits, nudes (representations), still lifes, photomosaics (photographs)
  - [Untitled], 1975; Louie, Reagan C.; 20 slides, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form, 1 résumé; color slides; Measurements:; 35 mm (Box 28)
  - [Untitled], 1976; Moino, Mario; 4 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 17)
    Keywords: nudes (representations), figures (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1976; Rubinfien, Leo; 15 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 14.5 x 18 inches, including mat (Box 18)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), cityscapes (representations), townscapes (representations), portraits
  - [Untitled], 1977; Gruda-Dodziuk, Kassia; 17 prints,1 submission form, 1 miscellaneous document; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 19)
  - Naturally Ripened Fruit, 1977; Malis, Larry Allan; 12 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form, 1 book of photographs; black-and-white photocopies; Measurements:; 8.5 x 11 inches (Box 28)
  - [Untitled], 1977; Harris, Honathan; 12; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 20)
    Keywords: nature photography, landscapes (representations)
  - Studio Lighting, 1978; Chan, Amos; 7 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 21)
    Keywords: portraits, still lifes, close-up views
  - Vicksburg Battlefield Views, 1978; Williams, William; 8 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 22)
    Keywords: Vicksburg-Mississippi, landscapes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1979; diCorcia, Philip-Lorca; 15 prints, 1 artist statement; color photographs; Measurements:; 14 x 17 inches (Box 23)
    Keywords: portraits, night photography, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1979; Feresten, Timothy; 20 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 24)
    Keywords: portraits, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1979; Frey, Mary; 16 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 14 x 17 inches (Box 25)
    Keywords: portraits, families
  - [Untitled], 1979; Hayden, Jacqueline; 16 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 26)
    Keywords: portraits, documentary photography, women (female humans), children (people by age group)
  - [Untitled], 1979; Lyons, Robert Allan; 17 prints, 1 artist statement; color photographs; Measurements:; 9 x 18 inches, including mat (Box 27)
  - [Untitled], 1980; Cataldo, Henry; 25 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 11 x 14 inches to 13.5 x 17 inches (Box 29)
    Keywords: documentary photography, landscapes (representations), nature photography
  - [Untitled], 1980; Crescensi, Christine; 27 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 30)
    Keywords: portraits, children (people by age group), religions (concept), documentary photography, urban areas
  - [Untitled], 1980; Griffin, Cathryn; 17 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 31)
    Keywords: domestic animals, rural areas
  - [Untitled], 1980; Leivick, Joel; 18 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form, 1 miscellaneous document; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 8 x 10 inches to 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 32)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), interior views, townscapes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1980; Scheer, Stephen; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 33)
    Keywords: documentary photography, portraits, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1981; Conner, Lois; 20 prints, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs, platinum prints; Measurements:; 14 x 18 inches (Box 34)
  - [Untitled], 1981; Lisak, Robert A.; 24 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 35)
    Keywords: portraits, interior views, landscapes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1981; Morell, Abelardo; 26 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 14 x 18 inches (Box 36)
    Keywords: documentary photography, portraits
  - [Untitled], 1981; Smith, Michael; 25 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 37)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), nature photography, rural areas
  - [Untitled], 1981; Tortorici, Mary; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 38)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), portraits, children (people by age group), rural areas
  - [Untitled], 1982; Borowiec, Andrew; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 81)
    Keywords: documentary photography, cityscapes (representations), landscapes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1982; Brehe, Kathryn; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 82)
    Keywords: cityscapes (representations), architecture (object genre)
  - [Untitled], 1982; Burns, Patrick; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 8 x 10 inches to 6.5 x 16.5 inches, including mat (Box 83)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), urban areas, industrial districts, panoramas
  - [Untitled], 1982; Bush, Andrew; 12 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 84)
    Keywords: interior views, still lifes
  - [Untitled], 1982; Paddock, Eric; 22 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 85)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), industrial districts, nature photography
  - [Untitled], 1982; Purtell, Sergio; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 86)
    Keywords: children (people by age group), portraits, documentary photography
  - [Untitled], 1982; Raymond, Sarah; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 87)
    Keywords: portraits, women (female humans)
  - [Untitled], 1983; Anos-Bertsos, Aspasia; 20 slides, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white slides; Measurements:; 35 mm (Box 39)
    Keywords: photomosaics (photographs), figures (representation), collages (visual works)
  - [Untitled], 1983; Brown, Thomas M.; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 40)
    Keywords: portraits, documentary photography
  - [Untitled], 1983; Dufresne, Walter; 25 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 41)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), cityscapes (representations), industrial districts
  - [Untitled], 1983; Lawton, Joseph; 17 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 42)
    Keywords: Guatemala, documentary photography, photojournalism
  - [Untitled], 1983; Lipper, Susan; 13 prints,1 artist statement,1 submission form, 1 list of works, 1 page of notes; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches, including mat (Box 43)
  - [Untitled], 1983; Weiss-Lesser, Deborah; 17 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 16 inches, including mat (Box 44)
    Keywords: Connecticut, Rhode Island, landscapes (representations), townscapes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1984; Blados, Lori Ann Korowotny; 27 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 45)
    Keywords: high-schools (buildings), adolescence, documentary photography
  - [Untitled], 1984; Cooley, Renee; 19 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 46)
    Keywords: documentary photography, cityscapes (representations), portraits
  - [Untitled], 1984; Gaines, Karen Alice Kamball; 14 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 47)
    Keywords: documentary photography, portraits, women (female humans)
  - [Untitled], 1984; Geltman, Barry; 17 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 48)
  - [Untitled], 1984; Polishuk, Ruth; 18 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 49)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), architecture (object genre), rural areas
  - [Untitled], 1984; Walsh, Anita; 16 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 50)
  - [Untitled], 1985; Ayala, Michael; 21 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 51)
    Keywords: documentary photography, urban areas, women (female humans)
  - [Untitled], 1985; D'Amato, Paul; 19 prints, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 52)
    Keywords: exterior views, townscapes (representations), portraits
  - [Untitled], 1985; Andersson, Monika; 26; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 53)
  - [Untitled], 1985; Fausty, Edward A.; 12 prints, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 54)
    Keywords: interior views, close-up views
  - [Untitled], 1985; Fishbein, Anne; 57 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form, 2 miscellaneous documents; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 55)
    Keywords: portraits, urban areas, landscapes (representations), documentary photography
  - [Untitled], 1985; Henderson, Garry; 23; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches (Box 56)
    Keywords: cityscapes (representations), portraits, urban areas
  - [Untitled], 1985; Modica, Andrea; 21 prints, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs, platinum prints; Measurements:; range from 6 x 9 inches to 10 x 12 inches (Box 57)
  - [Untitled], 1985; Prifti, David; 10 prints, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 58)
  - [Untitled], 1986; Boyd, Jean Gordon; 19 prints,1 artist statement, 1 miscellaneous document; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 59)
    Keywords: portraits, nudes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1986; Dumais, Dianne; 21 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 60)
    Keywords: portraits, adolescence
  - [Group Photography Project], 1986; 12 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 62)
  - [Untitled], 1986; Kornfeld, Ann; 18 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 64)
    Keywords: New York, women (female humans), documentary photography, portraits
  - [Untitled], 1986; Marcy, John; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 65)
    Keywords: portraits, urban areas, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1986; Steinmetz, Mark; 25 prints, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 61)
    Keywords: portraits, children (people by age group), domestic animals
  - Unidentified [Luttrell, Mark?], 1986; 15 prints, 1 artist statement; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 10.25 x 7 inches, including mat (Box 63)
  - [Untitled], 1986; Whitney, Lynn; 21 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 14 x 17 inches (Box 66)
    Keywords: rural areas, portraits, religions (concept)
  - [Untitled], 1987; Abbott, Ken; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 67)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), nature photography, portraits
  - [Untitled], 1987; Anderson, Scott; 21 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 10 inches (Box 68)
    Keywords: architecture (object genre), nature photography, landscapes (representations), close-up views
  - [Untitled], 1987; Axelrod, Jane; 18 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 10 inches (Box 69)
    Keywords: portraits, landscapes (representations)
  - [Untitled], 1987; Mosier, Phillip Wayne; 17 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 10 inches (Box 70)
    Keywords: portraits, industrial districts
  - [Untitled], 1987; Stolnitz, Dia; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form, 7 miscellaneous documents; color photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 10 inches (Box 71)
    Keywords: still-lifes, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1987; Vega, Matthew; 25 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 72)
    Keywords: adolescence, documentary photography
  - [Untitled], 1987; Wood, Mark Wesley; 24 prints, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 73)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), nature photography, townscapes (representations), close-up views
  - [Group Photography Project], [1987]; 24; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 8 x 10 inches to 16 x 20 inches (Box 16)
  - [Untitled], 1988; Bach, Michael Patrick; 32 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 list of works; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 8 x 10 inches (Box 74)
    Keywords: portraits, urban areas, landscapes (representations), nature photography, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1988; Crewdson, Gregory; 20; color photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 75)
    Keywords: night photography, portraits, urban areas, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1988; Doherty, Dornith; 12 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 76)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), rural areas, nature photography
  - [Untitled], 1988; Ferrario, Paola; 14 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; range from 11 x 14 inches to 16 x 20 inches (Box 77)
    Keywords: women (female humans), portraits, rural areas, interior views
  - [Untitled], 1988; Pancer, Hally F.; 17 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 78)
  - [Untitled], 1988; Thalken, Constance J.; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 11 x 14 inches to 16 x 20 inches (Box 79)
    Keywords: portraits, industrial districts, rural areas, men (male humans)
  - [Untitled], 1988; Vizzini, Nancianne; 22 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 80)
    Keywords: women (female humans), nudes (representations), manipulated photographs
  - [Untitled], 1989; Adams, Marc; 19 prints, 1 submission form; black-and- white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 88)
    Keywords: landscapes (representations), industrial districts,
  - [Untitled], 1989; Choi, Bokyung; 18 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 89)
  - [Untitled], 1989; Giovinco, Steven; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 90)
  - [Untitled], 1989; Gonzales, Antonio Luis; 20 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 11 x 14 inches to 16 x 20 inches (Box 91)
  - [Untitled], 1989; Russomagno, Gabrielle; 23 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 11 x 14 inches to 16 x 20 inches (Box 92)
    Keywords: portraits, children (people by age group), women (female humans)
  - [Untitled], 1989; Smith, Steven B.; 13 prints, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 93)
    Keywords: portraits, interior views, fantasy
  - [Untitled], 1990; Belanger, Marion, 1957-; 18 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 13 x 16 inches to 16 x 20 inches (Box 94)
    Keywords: women (female humans), close-up views, feminism
  - [Untitled], 1990; Hofsess, Craig; 24 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 11 x 14 inches (Box 95)
    Keywords: documentary photography, rural areas, women (female humans)
  - [Untitled], 1990; Kannan, Maggie; 5 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 4 x 15.5 inches to 8 x 10 inches, including mat (Box 96)
    Keywords: studio portraits, nudes (representations), self portraits, panoramas
  - [Untitled], 1990; Kimball, Justin; 18 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; range from 8 x 10 inches to 16 x 20 inches (Box 97)
  - [Untitled], 1990; Marcuse, Tanya; 22 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form, 1 miscellaneous document; black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 98)
    Keywords: portraits, children (people by age group), women (female humans), rural areas
  - [Untitled], 1990; Murray, William, 1705-1793; 15 prints, 1 artist statement, 1 submission form; color photographs, black-and-white photographs; Measurements:; 16 x 20 inches (Box 99)
    Keywords: portraits, families, interior views